{
numb: 1, 
question:"Which of the following statements about the CPU's handling interrupts is incorrect? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"None of the other choices","The CPU branches to a new instruction sequence","The hardware saves the old PC location","The processor ceases to execute the current sequence of instructions"]
},{
numb: 2, 
question:"____ is the partitioning of a single server, each of which can support a different operating *", 
answer: "Virtualization",
options: [
"Multiprocessing","Multithreading","Shared processing","Virtualization"]
},{
numb: 3, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 1 nsec to access a word from the cache, 10 nsec to access a word from RAM, and 10 msec to access a word from the disk. If the cache hit rate is 95% and main memory hit rate is 99%, what is average time to access a word? *", 
answer: "b. 5,001.445 nsec",
options: [
"a. 1.445 nsec","b. 5,001.445 nsec","c. 5,000.495 nsec","d. 5,000.95 nsec"]
},{
numb: 4, 
question:"Booting a general purpose computer involves the following steps except *", 
answer: "b. Loading the command interpreter",
options: [
"a. Loading the OS","b. Loading the command interpreter","c. Loading one or more bootstrap loaders","d. Execution of a ROM-based POST sequence"]
},{
numb: 5, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), which of the following conditions is correct? *", 
answer: "Decreasing cost per bit",
options: [
"Decreasing access time","None of the other choices","Decreasing cost per bit","Decreasing capacity"]
},{
numb: 6, 
question:"The two basic types of processor registers are: *", 
answer: "General and special registers",
options: [
"User-visible and user-invisible registers","None of the other choices","Control and Status registers","General and special registers"]
},{
numb: 7, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 2 nsec to access a byte from the cache, 20 nsec to access a byte from RAM, and 10 msec to access a block of 1000 bytes from the disk. If a book has 1000 pages, each with 50 lines of 80 characters each, How long it will take to electronically scan the text for the case of the master copy being in each of the level as one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage)? *", 
answer: "4 msec, 40 msec, 20 sec",
options: [
"1 msec, 10 msec, 5 sec","1 msec, 10 msec, 10 sec","2 msec, 20 msec, 10 sec","4 msec, 40 msec, 20 sec"]
},{
numb: 8, 
question:"The main characteristics of layered system does not include: *", 
answer: "C. Each layer runs independently",
options: [
"A. Upper layer can only call functions of closely lower layer","B. Each layer has well defined functions","C. Each layer runs independently","D. Many layers"]
},{
numb: 9, 
question:"Which of special register in the CPU points to the top of the current stack in the memory? *", 
answer: "SP",
options: [
"PC","PSW","IR","SP"]
},{
numb: 10, 
question:"A CPU may have multiple execution units, so that can carry out multiple instructions in the same time is called: *", 
answer: "Superscalar",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Multicore","Pipeline","Superscalar"]
},{
numb: 11, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 2 nsec to access a word from the cache, 20 nsec to access a word from RAM, and 10 msec to access a word from the disk. If the cache hit rate is 95% and main memory hit rate is 99%, what is average time to access a word? *", 
answer: "5,002.89 nsec",
options: [
"5,000.99 nsec","5,002.89 nsec","2.89 nsec","5,001.9 nsec"]
},{
numb: 12, 
question:"Information that must be saved prior to the processor transferring control to the interrupt handler routine includes: *", 
answer: "PSW and PC",
options: [
"PSW","None of the other choices","PSW and Contents of processor registers","PSW and PC"]
},{
numb: 13, 
question:"Examples of general purpose stored program computers include the following except *", 
answer: "MP3 player",
options: [
"Personal computers","Network servers","Workstations","MP3 player"]
},{
numb: 14, 
question:"The ways that input/output can be done is? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"DMA (Direct Memory Access)","All of the other choices","Busy waiting","Interrupt"]
},{
numb: 15, 
question:"List of memory location, that contains the executable program, the program's data, and its stack is called: *", 
answer: "address space",
options: [
"set of resources","all of the other choices","address memory","address space"]
},{
numb: 16, 
question:"Which is not an example of a resource that is commonly space-multiplexed? *", 
answer: "CPU",
options: [
"Video RAM","Main memory","CPU","Hard drive"]
},{
numb: 17, 
question:"Which of the following is not a step in the boot process? *", 
answer: "The antivirus program checks all files for viruses",
options: [
"The BIOS is activated by powering on the CPU","Configuration and customization settings are checked","The antivirus program checks all files for viruses","The operating system is loaded into RAM"]
},{
numb: 18, 
question:"Which of special register contains the Mode Bit (user or kernel)? *", 
answer: "Program Status Word (PSW)",
options: [
"Program Counter (PC)","None of the other choices","Program Status Word (PSW)","Instruction Register (IR)"]
},{
numb: 19, 
question:"Which is not an example of a resource that is commonly time-multiplexed? *", 
answer: "Main memory",
options: [
"CPU","Graphics accelerator","Main memory","Network interface"]
},{
numb: 20, 
question:"Where is the position of the operating system in computer system:", 
answer: "Above the hardware and under the user interface program",
options: [
"Above the hardware and under the user interface program","Between the user interface program and the application Program","In user space","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 21, 
question:"Which of the main bus in the IBM PC computer that can run at 66 MHz and transfer 8 bytes at a time? *", 
answer: "PCI (Peripheral Component Interconnect)",
options: [
"PCI (Peripheral Component Interconnect)","ISA (Industry Standard Architecture)","None of the other choices","ISA and PCI"]
},{
numb: 22, 
question:"Which of the following statements about Electrically Erasable PROM (EEPROM) is correct? *", 
answer: "Can be erased and rewritten",
options: [
"Can be erased and rewritten","Unprogrammable","Volatile","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 23, 
question:"The major operating system services provide mechanisms for secure and efficient are: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Communication between processes","All of the other choices","Execution of a program, I/O operations performed by it, and detecting and reporting errors caused by it","File manipulation"]
},{
numb: 24, 
question:"Which of the following instructions should be allowed only in kernel mode? *", 
answer: "Disable all interrupts",
options: [
"ADD of two numbers","AND of two numbers","Disable all interrupts","Read the time-of-day clock"]
},{
numb: 25, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), which of the following conditions is correct? *", 
answer: "Increasing capacity",
options: [
"Increasing cost per bit","Decreasing access time","None of the other choices","Increasing capacity"]
},{
numb: 26, 
question:"The main characteristics of exokernels is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"A subset of the resources is given in user mode","The program, called the exokernel runs in kernel mode","Exokernels need only keep track of which virtual machine assigned which resource","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 27, 
question:"The language of the CPU is known as its *", 
answer: "Instruction set",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Instruction set","Register set","Control unit set"]
},{
numb: 28, 
question:"Which of special register contains the condition code bits, the CPU priority, the mode bit and other control bits)? *", 
answer: "Program Status Word (PSW)",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Program Counter (PC)","Instruction Register (IR)","Program Status Word (PSW)"]
},{
numb: 29, 
question:"Which of the following statements about Random Access Memory (RAM) is correct? *", 
answer: "Is volatile",
options: [
"Is volatile","Stores all the files on the computer","Can only be read sequentially","Is typically faster than cache memory"]
},{
numb: 30, 
question:"VMware Workstation is: *", 
answer: "Type 2 Hypervisor",
options: [
"Type 2 Hypervisor","Host Operating system","Type 1 Hypervisor","Guest Operating system"]
},{
numb: 31, 
question:"Which of the following is correct about advantages of layered system? *", 
answer: "Easier to extend and Easier to debug from lower to upper layer",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Easier to debug from lower to upper layer","Easier to extend and Easier to debug from lower to upper layer","Easier to extend"]
},{
numb: 32, 
question:"Which of the following instructions should be allowed only in kernel mode? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"All of the other choices","Change the memory map","Set the time-of-day clock","Disable all interrupts"]
},{
numb: 33, 
question:"Which of the following statements about the CMOS is incorrect? *", 
answer: "To contain BIOS",
options: [
"Is volatile","To contain BIOS","To hold the configuration parameters","To hold the current time and date"]
},{
numb: 34, 
question:"What part of the boot process determines whether the peripheral devices are working properly? *", 
answer: "POST",
options: [
"ROM","POST","CMOS","BIOS"]
},{
numb: 35, 
question:"The four main structural elements of a computer system are: *", 
answer: "Processor, Main Memory, I/O Modules, System Bus",
options: [
"Processor, Registers, I/O Modules, Main Memory","None of the other choices","Processor, Registers, Main Memory, System Bus","Processor, Main Memory, I/O Modules, System Bus"]
},{
numb: 36, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), which of the following conditions is correct? *", 
answer: "Increasing access time",
options: [
"Decreasing capacity","None of the other choices","Increasing cost per bit","Increasing access time"]
},{
numb: 37, 
question:"What is not a main function of an operating system? *", 
answer: "Provide user interfaces",
options: [
"Provide the users with an extended (virtual) machine","Manage the I/O devices","Provide user interfaces","Support virtual memory"]
},{
numb: 38, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), the following conditions apply: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Increasing capacity","Decreasing cost per bit","All of the other choices","Increasing access time"]
},{
numb: 39, 
question:"Which of the following is not a operating mode of CPU *", 
answer: "Management mode",
options: [
"Kernel mode","User mode","Management mode","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 40, 
question:"A special register that contains the address of the next instruction to be fetched is called: *", 
answer: "Program Counter (PC)",
options: [
"Instruction Register (IR)","All of the other choices","Program Counter (PC)","Program Status Word (PSW)"]
},{
numb: 41, 
question:"Which of the following operating systems is a example of monolithic system? *", 
answer: "MS-DOS",
options: [
"MS-DOS","Mac OS","UNIX","Windows XP"]
},{
numb: 42, 
question:"A CPU may have two or more complete processors, so that can carry out multiple threads in the same time is called: *", 
answer: "Multicore",
options: [
"Pipeline","Multicore","None of the other choices","Superscalar"]
},{
numb: 43, 
question:"Which of the following instructions should be allowed in user mode? *", 
answer: "Read the time-of-day clock",
options: [
"Read the time-of-day clock","Set the time-of-day clock","Disable all interrupts","Change the memory map"]
},{
numb: 44, 
question:"The main bus in the IBM PC computer are: *", 
answer: "ISA and PCI",
options: [
"PCI (Peripheral Component Interconnect)","ISA and PCI","None of the other choices","ISA (Industry Standard Architecture)"]
},{
numb: 45, 
question:"The general role of an operating system is to: *", 
answer: "Provide a set of services to system users",
options: [
"Provide a set of services to system users","Act as an interface between various computers","None of the other choices","Manage files for application programs"]
},{
numb: 46, 
question:"The operating system structure in which the communication between requesting process and responding process is message passing? *", 
answer: "Client - Server Model",
options: [
"All of the other choices","Monolithic Systems","MS - DOS","Client - Server Model"]
},{
numb: 47, 
question:"What is interrupt vector? *", 
answer: "Part of memory which contains the addresses of interrupt handlers",
options: [
"Part of memory which contains the addresses of interrupt handlers","The addresses of interrupt handlers","A signal an I/O device sends to CPU","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 48, 
question:"Which of the following actions generates an external interrupt? *", 
answer: "An input/output operation is completed.",
options: [
"A page that does not exist in the main memory is accessed by the virtual storage management.","An input/output operation is completed.","Division by zero occurs.","A system call instruction is executed."]
},{
numb: 49, 
question:"An operating system *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Manages software resources in a computer system","Deals with complex hardware resources and provides the user a virtual/extended machine that is much easier to deal with than the physical machine","Manages hardware resources in a computer system","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 50, 
question:"A CPU may have separate fech, decode and execute units, so that can carry out three steps of the three instructions in the same time is called: *", 
answer: "Pipeline",
options: [
"Pipeline","None of the other choices","Superscalar","Multicore"]
},{
numb: 51, 
question:"The basic idea behind the microkernel design is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Only one module runs in kernel mode","To achive high reliability by splitting operating system up into small, well-defined modules","All other modules run as relatively powerless ordinary user processes","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 52, 
question:"What does the virtual machine monitor do? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Does the multiprogramming","Provides sevral virtual machines to the next layer up","All of the other choices","Runs on the bare hardware."]
},{
numb: 53, 
question:"Which is the fastest bus in the IBM PC computer? *", 
answer: "PCI (Peripheral Component Interconnect)",
options: [
"PCI (Peripheral Component Interconnect)","IDE (Integrated Drive Electronic)","ISA (Industry Standard Architecture)","USB (Universal Serial BUS)"]
},{
numb: 54, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 2 nsec to access a word from the cache, 10 nsec to access a word from RAM, and 10 msec to access a word from the disk. If the cache hit rate is 95% and main memory hit rate is 99%, what is average time to access a word? *", 
answer: "5,002.395 nsec",
options: [
"5,000.495 nsec","5,001.9 nsec","2.395 nsec","5,002.395 nsec"]
},{
numb: 55, 
question:"Which of the following conditions that causes the processes to be terminated, when the processes executes a system call tell the OS to fininsh some other process? *", 
answer: "Killed by another process (involuntary)",
options: [
"Normal exit (voluntary)","Error exit (voluntary)","Fatal error (involuntary)","Killed by another process (involuntary)"]
},{
numb: 56, 
question:"Which of the following conditions that causes the processes to be terminated, when the processes have a program bug? *", 
answer: "Fatal error (involuntary)",
options: [
"Fatal error (involuntary)","Error exit (voluntary)","Normal exit (voluntary)","Killed by another process (involuntary)"]
},{
numb: 57, 
question:"Operating system abstraction supports the ability to have ______ operation even when there is only one CPU available *", 
answer: "pseudoparallelism",
options: [
"multiple","none of the other choices","parallel","pseudoparallelism"]
},{
numb: 58, 
question:"What is the 'sequential processes' concept? *", 
answer: "No concurrency inside a process; everything happens sequentiall",
options: [
"There are both many CPU and many PC","None of the other choices","All process is executed in concurrency","No concurrency inside a process; everything happens sequentiall"]
},{
numb: 59, 
question:"How many percent of the CPU time is wasted, when a computer system has enough room to hold two program and these programs are idle waiting for I/O half the time? *", 
answer: "25%",
options: [
"75%","50%","25%","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 60, 
question:"____ is the act of allowing only one process to have access to a dedicated resource *", 
answer: "Mutual exclusion",
options: [
"Mutual exclusion","Circular wait","No preemption","Resource holdin"]
},{
numb: 61, 
question:"Which of the following statements about user-level threads and kernel-level threads is correct? *", 
answer: "Both user-level threads and kernel-level threads can write into each other's memory space",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Both user-level threads and kernel-level threads can write into each other's memory space","Kernel-level thread scheduling is faster than user-level thread scheduling","Both user-level threads and kernel-level threads use OS services via system calls"]
},{
numb: 62, 
question:"Which of the following cannot be shared among different threads of a process? *", 
answer: "Stack",
options: [
"Stack","Process code","File handles","Process data"]
},{
numb: 63, 
question:"A ____ is a portion of a process that can run independently *", 
answer: "thread",
options: [
"thread","program","miniprocess","subprocess"]
},{
numb: 64, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. . Determine the average waiting time for FCFS scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead . *", 
answer: "12,8 minutes",
options: [
"18 minutes","18.8 minutes","17 minutes","12,8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 65, 
question:"Which of the following is appropriate to release page table and pages? *", 
answer: "Process termination time",
options: [
"Process creation","Process termination time","Page fault time","Process execution"]
},{
numb: 66, 
question:"Which of the events that causes the processes to be created, when the operation system creates a new process and runs the next job from the input queue? *", 
answer: "Initiation of a batch job",
options: [
"Initiation of a batch job","User request to create a new process","System initialization","Execution of a process creation system call"]
},{
numb: 67, 
question:"How many percent of the CPU time is wasted, when a computer system has enough room to hold two program and these programs are idle waiting for I/O 10% of the time? *", 
answer: "1%",
options: [
"99%","1%","None of the other choices","90%"]
},{
numb: 68, 
question:"What happens when a thread calls Down (S) when it wants to enter its critical section, where S is a binary semaphore set to 1? *", 
answer: "The thread is allowed to enter its critical section and S is decremented.",
options: [
"The thread is blocked and added to a queue of waiting threads.","The semaphore is set to 2.","The thread is allowed to enter its critical section and S is decremented.","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 69, 
question:"Which of the following statements is a hardware solution to the critical region problem? *", 
answer: "TSL",
options: [
"TSL","Semaphore","None of the other choices","Shared memory"]
},{
numb: 70, 
question:"Which of the following is not true about process hierarchy? *", 
answer: "A process may have more than one parent",
options: [
"Window has no concept of a process hierarchy","In Unix, a process and all its children and further descendants together form a process group","A process creates child process. The child process can itself creates more processes, forming a process hierarchy","A process may have more than one parent"]
},{
numb: 71, 
question:"Which conditions of mutual exclusion does the Strict Alternation (Software proposal) violate *", 
answer: "No process running outside its critical region may block another process",
options: [
"No process running outside its critical region may block another process","No assumptions made about speeds or numbers of CPUs","No process must wait forever to enter its critical region","No two processes simultaneously in critical region"]
},{
numb: 72, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. Their (externally determined) priorities are 3, 5, 2, 1, and 4, respectively, with 5 being the highest priority. Determine the average waiting time for Priority scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead. *", 
answer: "10,8 minutes",
options: [
"16,8 minutes","12,8 minutes","54 minutes","10,8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 73, 
question:"hich statement about disadvantage of Disabling interrupts, (the hardware solution to the critical region problem) is correct? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Permit process use command privileges: Danger!","If process is locked in Critical Section: System Halt","All of the other choices","Don't ensure Mutual Exclusion for the system with N CPUs"]
},{
numb: 74, 
question:"How many percent is CPU utilization, when a computer system has enough room to hold two program and these programs are idle waiting for I/O 10% of the time? *", 
answer: "99%",
options: [
"1%","99%","None of the other choices","90%"]
},{
numb: 75, 
question:"What is the purpose of process synchronization? *", 
answer: "Avoid race condition",
options: [
"Avoid race condition","None of the other choices","Let different users run different processes independently","Avoid deadlock"]
},{
numb: 76, 
question:"Which of the following operating system has the concept of a process hierarchy? *", 
answer: "Unix",
options: [
"Win32","CP/M","MS-DOS","Unix"]
},{
numb: 77, 
question:"OS Windows use system call_____, while OS Unix use system call______ to terminate processes normally *", 
answer: "ExitProcess; exit",
options: [
"terminate; ExitProcess","exit; ExitProcess","ExitProcess; exit","ExitProcess; terminate"]
},{
numb: 78, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is correct, when the scheduler picks a process from the ready queue to run? *", 
answer: "Ready -> running",
options: [
"Running -> ready","Ready -> running","Blocked (waiting) -> ready","Running -> Blocked (waiting)"]
},{
numb: 79, 
question:"In a single processor system, mutual exclusion can be guaranteed by:", 
answer: "Disabling interrupts",
options: [
"Overlapping processes","Interleaving processes","Disabling interrupts","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 80, 
question:"In order to implement mutual exclusion on a critical resource for competing processes, only one program at a time should be allowed: *", 
answer: "In the critical region of the program",
options: [
"None of the other choices","To exhibit cooperation","To perform message passing","In the critical region of the program"]
},{
numb: 81, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is illegal? *", 
answer: "Ready -> Blocked (waiting)",
options: [
"Blocked (waiting) -> ready","Ready -> Blocked (waiting)","Running -> Blocked (waiting)","Running -> ready"]
},{
numb: 82, 
question:"Which of the following conditions that causes the processes to be terminated, when a processes have done their work? *", 
answer: "Normal exit (voluntary )",
options: [
"Normal exit (voluntary )","Error exit (voluntary)","Fatal error (involuntary)","Killed by another process (involuntary)"]
},{
numb: 83, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about user-level threads? *", 
answer: "With user-level threads, customized scheduling algorithms cannot be implemented",
options: [
"User-level threads are more efficient than kernel threads, in the sense that they do not need kernel calls to switch among threads","With user-level threads, customized scheduling algorithms cannot be implemented","User-level threads cannot be preempted by clock interrupts unless the whole process' quantum has been used up","If one user-level thread makes a blocking system call, the system will block the entire process (which contains that user-level thread)"]
},{
numb: 84, 
question:"Which of the following about Atomic action is true? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Possibly going to sleep","All of the other choices","Checking the value","Changing the value"]
},{
numb: 85, 
question:"A entry of the Process table is called: *", 
answer: "Process control block",
options: [
"Process control block","Process management block","All of the other choices","Process check block"]
},{
numb: 86, 
question:"What is Software proposal in the solution of Mutual exclusion with Busy waiting *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Peterson's Solution","All of the other choices","Lock Variables","Strict Alternation"]
},{
numb: 87, 
question:"Which conditions of mutual exclusion does the Lock Variables (Software proposal ) violate *", 
answer: "No two processes simultaneously in critical region",
options: [
"No assumptions made about speeds or numbers of CPUs","No two processes simultaneously in critical region","No process must wait forever to enter its critical region","No process running outside its critical region may block another process"]
},{
numb: 88, 
question:"A process where no concurrency inside process; everything happens sequentially is called: *", 
answer: "Sequential process",
options: [
"Random access process","Sequential process","Sequential access process","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 89, 
question:"When selecting the proper time quantum it should be long enough to allow ____ percent of the CPU cycles to run to completion *", 
answer: "80",
options: [
"40","100","80","20"]
},{
numb: 90, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. Determine the average waiting time for SJF (Shortest job first) scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead. *", 
answer: "8 minutes",
options: [
"18.8 minutes","6 minutes","8 minutes","14 minutes"]
},{
numb: 91, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. . Determine the average turnaround time for FCFS scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead. *", 
answer: "18.8 minutes",
options: [
"20 minutes","18 minutes","17 minutes","18.8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 92, 
question:"How many percent is CPU utilization, when a computer system has enough room to hold two program and these programs are idle waiting for I/O half the time? *", 
answer: "75%",
options: [
"75%","50%","25%","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 93, 
question:"A computer has 2GB RAM of which the operating system occupies 1GB.The processes are all 450 MB and have the same characteristics. How many percent of the CPU time is wasted, when these programs are idle waiting for I/O 20% of the time? *", 
answer: "4%",
options: [
"90%","None of the other choices","4%","96%"]
},{
numb: 94, 
question:"How many ways are Thread implemented? *", 
answer: "3",
options: [
"3","2","1","4"]
},{
numb: 95, 
question:"What is not a field in the process table that relates memory management? *", 
answer: "Pointer to program segment info",
options: [
"Pointer to data segment info","Pointer to stack segment info","Pointer to text segment info","Pointer to program segment info"]
},{
numb: 96, 
question:"Which is the correct description of transitions between process states below? (see picture) *", 
answer: "1: Process blocks for input; 2: Input becomes available; 3: Scheduler picks this process; 4: Scheduler picks another process",
options: [
"1/1","Captionless Image","1: Process blocks for input; 2: Input becomes available; 3: Scheduler picks another process; 4: Scheduler picks this process","1: Process blocks for input; 2: Scheduler picks this process; 3: Scheduler picks another process; 4: Input becomes available"]
},{
numb: 97, 
question:"A computer has 2GB RAM of which the operating system occupies 1GB.The processes are all 450 MB and have the same characteristics. How many percent is CPU utilization when these programs are idle waiting for I/O 20% of the time? *", 
answer: "96%",
options: [
"90%","None of the other choices","96%","4%"]
},{
numb: 98, 
question:"Which of the events that causes the processes to be created, when a running process creates one or more new process to help it to do its job? *", 
answer: "Execution of a process creation system call",
options: [
"Execution of a process creation system call","Initiation of a batch job","User request to create a new process","System initialization"]
},{
numb: 99, 
question:"The following requirement must be met by any facility or capability that is to provide support for mutual exclusion: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Only one process at a time can be allowed into a critical section","No assumption can be made about relative process speeds","All of the other choices","A process remains in its critical region for a finite time only"]
},{
numb: 100, 
question:"Which is a advantage of implementing threads in the kernel? *", 
answer: "Is good for multiprocessor architecture and if one thread is blocked does not cause the other thread to be blocked",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Is good for multiprocessor architecture and if one thread is blocked does not cause the other thread to be blocked","If one thread is blocked does not cause the other thread to be blocked","Is good for multiprocessor architecture"]
},{
numb: 101, 
question:"Critical Region (Section) concept used in interprocess communication is: *", 
answer: "A part of the program where the shared memory is accessed",
options: [
"A part of shared memory","None of the other choices","A part of the program where the shared memory is accessed","A part of shared data"]
},{
numb: 102, 
question:"OS Win32 use system call_____, while OS Unix use system call______ to create a new process *", 
answer: "CreateProcess; fork",
options: [
"fork, CreateProcess","CreateProcess; fork","copy, CreateProcess","CreateProcess; copy"]
},{
numb: 103, 
question:"Which statement about disabling interrupts to resolve race conditions is wrong? *", 
answer: "B. User-mode programs are the best place to invoke disableInterrupt()",
options: [
"A. Disabling/enabling interrupts may negatively affect the I/O system","B. User-mode programs are the best place to invoke disableInterrupt()","C. In theory, a program can disable interrupts when it enters a critical section, and re-enable interrupts when finished with a critical section, to eliminate race conditions","D. Programs with infinite loops in their critical sections are a significant problem with the interrupt-based approach"]
},{
numb: 104, 
question:"Which of the events that causes the processes to be created, when an operation system is booted? *", 
answer: "System initialization",
options: [
"System initialization","Execution of a process creation system call","User request to create a new process","Initiation of a batch job"]
},{
numb: 105, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is legal? *", 
answer: "Running -> ready",
options: [
"Blocked (waiting) -> runnig","Ready -> Blocked (waiting)","None of the other choices","Running -> ready"]
},{
numb: 106, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is correct, when the external event for which a process was waiting happens? *", 
answer: "Blocked (waiting) -> ready",
options: [
"Running -> Blocked (waiting)","Running -> ready","Ready -> running","Blocked (waiting) -> ready"]
},{
numb: 107, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is correct, when the operating system discovers that process can not continue right now because of is not enough resource? *", 
answer: "Running -> Blocked (waiting)",
options: [
"Running -> ready","Blocked (waiting) -> ready","Ready -> running","Running -> Blocked (waiting)"]
},{
numb: 108, 
question:"Which of the following statements about semaphores is true? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"If several processes attempt a P(S) operation simultaneously, only one process should be allowed to proceed.","A semaphore implementation should guarantee that processes do not suffer indefinite postponement.","All of the other choices","P and V (Down and Up) operations should be indivisible operations"]
},{
numb: 109, 
question:"Which of the following conditions must be held to provide good solution for mutual exclusion? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"1/1","No process running outside its critical region may block another process","No process must wait forever to enter its critical region","No two processes simultaneously in critical region"]
},{
numb: 110, 
question:"In terms of disk storage efficiency, the method of 'Backing up pages dynamically' in comparison with the method of 'Paging to a static swap area' is *", 
answer: "Better",
options: [
"Nearly equal","Better","Equal","Worse"]
},{
numb: 111, 
question:"A well-known operating system for Handheld Computer is: *", 
answer: "Symbian OS and Palm OS",
options: [
"e-COS","TinyOS","Symbian OS and Palm OS","MS-DOS"]
},{
numb: 112, 
question:"Critical Region (Section) concept used in interprocess communication is: *", 
answer: "A part of the program where the shared memory is accessed",
options: [
"None of the other choices","A part of shared data","A part of shared memory","A part of the program where the shared memory is accessed"]
},{
numb: 113, 
question:"When there is an excessive amount of page swapping between main memory and secondary storage, the operation becomes inefficient, which is called ____. *", 
answer: "thrashing",
options: [
"excessive demand paging","over swapping","hot swapping","thrashing"]
},{
numb: 114, 
question:"Suppose a virtual address space of 2^24 words and the page size is 2^12 words. If the virtual address is 123456 in Hexadecimal, what would be the page number in Hexadecimal? *", 
answer: "123",
options: [
"12345","1234","123456","123"]
},{
numb: 115, 
question:"A system with 32 bit virtual address. If the page size is 4 KB and each table entry occupies 4 bytes, what is the size of the page table? *", 
answer: "4 MB",
options: [
"4 MB","8 MB","2 MB","1 MB"]
},{
numb: 116, 
question:"Which of these statements about the Inverted Page Table are true? *", 
answer: "An entry contains the pair (process, virtual page) mapped into the corresponding page frame",
options: [
"An entry contains the pair (process, offset) mapped into the corresponding page frame","An entry contains the pair (segment, virtual page) mapped into the corresponding page frame","An entry contains the pair (process, virtual page) mapped into the corresponding page frame","An entry contains the pair (segment, offset) mapped into the corresponding page frame"]
},{
numb: 117, 
question:"In terms of speed the best method of Dynamic Storage-Allocation is: *", 
answer: "First fit",
options: [
"Worst fit","Best fit","Next fit","First fit"]
},{
numb: 118, 
question:"A process where no concurrency inside process; everything happens sequentially is called : *", 
answer: "Sequential process",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Sequential access process","Sequential process","Random access process"]
},{
numb: 119, 
question:"What is not a field in the process table that relates process management? *", 
answer: "User ID, Group ID",
options: [
"CPU time used","PC, PSW, SP","User ID, Group ID","Process ID"]
},{
numb: 120, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is correct, when the external event for which a process was waiting happens? *", 
answer: "Blocked (waiting) -> ready",
options: [
"Ready -> running","Running -> Blocked (waiting)","Blocked (waiting) -> ready","Running -> ready"]
},{
numb: 121, 
question:"Which is the maximum partition size, if the FAT type is FAT-32 and the block size is 4 KB? *", 
answer: "1 TB",
options: [
"256 MB","1 TB","512 MB","128 MB"]
},{
numb: 122, 
question:"Where should be put the page replacement algorithm In Mach model of Page fault handling with an external pager? *", 
answer: "In the external pager running in user space",
options: [
"In the page fault handler that is part of the kernel","In the external pager running in user space","All of the other choices","In the low-level MMU handler"]
},{
numb: 123, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 1 nsec to access a byte from the cache, 10 nsec to access a byte from RAM, and 5 msec to access a block of 1000 bytes from the disk. If a book has 1000 pages, each with 25 lines of 80 characters each, How long it will take to electronically scan the text for the case of the master copy being in each of the level as one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage)? *", 
answer: "2 msec, 20 msec, 10 sec",
options: [
"4 msec, 40 msec, 20 sec","1 msec, 10 msec, 5 sec","2 msec, 20 msec, 10 sec","1 msec, 10 msec, 10 sec"]
},{
numb: 124, 
question:"What is correct about trap instructions and interrupts? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"An interrupt is caused by an external event","Trap instruction switches the execution mode of a CPU from the user mode to the kernel mode.","A trap instruction is caused by a user program to invoke functions in the OS kernel","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 125, 
question:"Which of the following operating system has the concept of a process hierarchy? *", 
answer: "Unix",
options: [
"Win32","CP/M","Unix","MS-DOS"]
},{
numb: 126, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), which of the following conditions is correct? *", 
answer: "Increasing capacity",
options: [
"Decreasing access time","Increasing capacity","Increasing cost per bit","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 127, 
question:"Assume that the Page Table below is in effect: Page Number: 0 1 2 3; Page Frame Number: 8 10 5 11. The number of lines per page is 400. The actual memory location for line 1634 is ____. *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"None of the other choices","1634","3","4434"]
},{
numb: 128, 
question:"How many percent of the CPU time is wasted, when a computer system has enough room to hold two program and these programs are idle waiting for I/O half the time? *", 
answer: "25%",
options: [
"25%","75%","None of the other choices","50%"]
},{
numb: 129, 
question:"Working set model is used for: *", 
answer: "Finding the minimum number of frames necessary for a job so that jobs can be run without "thrashing"",
options: [
"Determining whether page replacement is needed","Finding the average number of frames a job will need to run smoothly","All of the other choices","Finding the minimum number of frames necessary for a job so that jobs can be run without 'thrashing'"]
},{
numb: 130, 
question:"An arrival message causes the system to create a new thread to handle this message. This new thread is call______ *", 
answer: "Pop-up",
options: [
"Activator","Upcall","Pop-up","Distributed"]
},{
numb: 131, 
question:"What is Higher-level proposal in the solution of Mutual exclusion and Synchronization? *", 
answer: "Monitors",
options: [
"Monitors","Message passing","Disable Interrupts","Peterson's Solution"]
},{
numb: 132, 
question:"What is the characteristic of the second generation of operating system? *", 
answer: "Transistors, batch systems",
options: [
"ICs and multiprogramming","Transistors, batch systems","Vacuum tubes, plug boards","Personal computers, single user, multitasking"]
},{
numb: 133, 
question:"What is the main characteristic of real-time operating system? *", 
answer: "Time is key parameter",
options: [
"Multiple CPU","Time-sharing","Time is key parameter","Many I/O devices"]
},{
numb: 134, 
question:"LRU replaces the page that has spent the *", 
answer: "longest time in memory without being referenced",
options: [
"longest time in memory","shortest time in memory","longest time in memory without being referenced","shortest time in memory without being referenced"]
},{
numb: 135, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about user-level threads? *", 
answer: "B. With user-level threads, customized scheduling algorithms cannot be implemented",
options: [
"A. User-level threads are more efficient than kernel threads, in the sense that they do not need kernel calls to switch among threads","B. With user-level threads, customized scheduling algorithms cannot be implemented","C. User-level threads cannot be preempted by clock interrupts unless the whole process' quantum has been used up","D. If one user-level thread makes a blocking system call, the system will block the entire process (which contains that user-level thread)"]
},{
numb: 136, 
question:"A computer has four page frames. The time of loading, time of last access, and the R and M bits for each page are as shown below (the times are in clock ticks). Which page will NRU replace?", 
answer: "0",
options: [
"0","1","2","3"]
},{
numb: 137, 
question:"A computer with a 32-bit address uses a two-level page table. Virtual addresses are split into a 9-bit top-level page table field, an 11-bit second-level page table field, and an offset. How many pages are there in the address space? *", 
answer: "2^20 pages",
options: [
"2^23 pages","2^20 pages","2^22 pages","2^21 pages"]
},{
numb: 138, 
question:"Which is not true about 'Backing up pages dynamically'? *", 
answer: "Needs less main memory than the method "Paging to a static swap area"",
options: [
"Requires a disk map in memory","Pages do not have fixed swap area on the disk","When a page is swapped out, an empty disk page is chosen on the fly and disk map is updated accordingly","Needs less main memory than the method 'Paging to a static swap area'"]
},{
numb: 139, 
question:"What is not the technique of implementation for Virtual Memory? *", 
answer: "Partition",
options: [
"Partition","Segmentation","Paging","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 140, 
question:"As one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage), which of the following conditions is correct? *", 
answer: "Decreasing cost per bit",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Decreasing cost per bit","Decreasing access time","Decreasing capacity"]
},{
numb: 141, 
question:"Which of the following actions generates an external interrupt? *", 
answer: "An input/output operation is completed.",
options: [
"A page that does not exist in the main memory is accessed by the virtual storage management.","A system call instruction is executed.","Division by zero occurs.","An input/output operation is completed."]
},{
numb: 142, 
question:"Which is not true about the method of backing store: 'Paging to a static swap area'? *", 
answer: "Requires a disk map in memory",
options: [
"The swap area on the disk is as large as the process virtual address space","Calculating the address in swap area requires knowing only where the process' paging area begins","A page that is in memory always have shadow copy on disk","Requires a disk map in memory"]
},{
numb: 143, 
question:"The page size that is too small will generate ____ *", 
answer: "Very long Page tables",
options: [
"More difficult to calculate actual position","Very long Page tables","Excessive internal fragmentation","Excessive external fragmentation"]
},{
numb: 144, 
question:"Assume jobs A-D arrive in quick succession in the READY queue. Using round robin scheduling (quantum=4), the turnaround time for job B is ____. Arrival time: 0 1 2 3; Job: A B C D; CPU cycle: 8 4 9 5 *", 
answer: "7",
options: [
"24","20","22","7"]
},{
numb: 145, 
question:"Which of the following is true about Atomic action on semaphores? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Changing the value","Possibly going to sleep","Checking the value","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 146, 
question:"Which of the following statements is a hardware solution to the critical region problem? *", 
answer: "TSL",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Semaphore","Shared memory","TSL"]
},{
numb: 147, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. Their (externally determined) priorities are 3, 5, 2, 1, and 4, respectively, with 5 being the highest priority. Determine the average waiting time for Priority scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead. *", 
answer: "10,8 minutes",
options: [
"12,8 minutes","10,8 minutes","54 minutes","16,8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 148, 
question:"If there are 128 pages and the page size is 32 K words, what is the length of logical address? *", 
answer: "22 bits",
options: [
"24 bits","26 bits","30 bits","22 bits"]
},{
numb: 149, 
question:"Which of the following information bits in the entry of page table is used to indicate locked page? *", 
answer: "Caching disabled",
options: [
"Modified bit","Caching disabled","Present/absent bit","Referenced bit"]
},{
numb: 150, 
question:"The modified/dirty bit is used for the purpose of: *", 
answer: "Reduce the average time required to service page faults",
options: [
"Dynamic allocation of memory used by one process to another","Reduce the average time required to service page faults","None of the other choices","Implementing FIFO page replacement algorithm"]
},{
numb: 151, 
question:"What is not a main function of an operating system? *", 
answer: "Provide user interfaces",
options: [
"Manage the I/O devices","Provide the users with an extended (virtual) machine","Provide user interfaces","Support virtual memory"]
},{
numb: 152, 
question:"Which of following statements about the memory hierarchy is false? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"Gigabytes of slow cheap disk storage","None of the other choices","Some medium-speed medium price main memory","Small amount of fast expensive memory-cache"]
},{
numb: 153, 
question:"A simple structuring model for monolithic system includes: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"All of the other choices","A main program that invokes the requested service procedure","A set of service procedures that carry out the system calls","A set of utility procedures that help the service procedures"]
},{
numb: 154, 
question:"Which kind of tables is used in the segmentation? *", 
answer: "Both Global Descriptor Table (GDT) and Local Descriptor Table (LDT )",
options: [
"Local Descriptor Table (LDT )","None of the other choices","Both Global Descriptor Table (GDT) and Local Descriptor Table (LDT )","Global Descriptor Table (GDT)"]
},{
numb: 155, 
question:"Consider a swapping system in which the memory consists of the following hole sizes: 10K, 4K, 20K, 15K, 9K. Assume best fit algorithm is used. Which holes are taken for successive segment requests of 8K, 12K, 10K? *", 
answer: "9K, 15K, 10K",
options: [
"10K, 15K, 20K","10K, 20K, 15K","20K, 15K, 10K","9K, 15K, 10K"]
},{
numb: 156, 
question:"In some thread systems, a thread want be blocked until an other thread has exited. It can establish this goal by calling______ *", 
answer: "thread_wait",
options: [
"thread_yield","thread_wait","thread_create","thread_exit"]
},{
numb: 157, 
question:"Consider a computer system that has cache memory, main memory (RAM) and disk, and OS uses virtual memory. It takes 1 nsec to access a byte from the cache, 10 nsec to access a byte from RAM, and 5 msec to access a block of 1000 bytes from the disk. If a book has 1000 pages, each with 50 lines of 80 characters each, How long it will take to electronically scan the text for the case of the master copy being in each of the level as one proceeds down the memory hierarchy (from inboard memory to offline storage)? *", 
answer: "4 msec, 40 msec, 20 sec",
options: [
"4 msec, 40 msec, 20 sec","1 msec, 10 msec, 10 sec","2 msec, 20 msec, 10 sec","1 msec, 10 msec, 5 sec"]
},{
numb: 158, 
question:"Which of the following is a preemptive scheduling algorithm *", 
answer: "Round Robin",
options: [
"Round Robin","None of the other choices","Shortest Job First","FCFS"]
},{
numb: 159, 
question:"Which of the following instructions should be allowed in user mode? *", 
answer: "Read the time-of-day clock",
options: [
"Disable all interrupts","Read the time-of-day clock","Change the memory map","Set the time-of-day clock"]
},{
numb: 160, 
question:"Examples of general purpose stored program computers include the following except *", 
answer: "MP3 player",
options: [
"Network servers","Workstations","MP3 player","Personal computers"]
},{
numb: 161, 
question:"When a virtual memory system manages memory in fixed length units, which of the following terms correctly represents its unit? *", 
answer: "Page",
options: [
"Segment","Block","Frame","Page"]
},{
numb: 162, 
question:"At which level in Protection Rings on the Pentium the System calls reside *", 
answer: "1",
options: [
"0","2","1","3"]
},{
numb: 163, 
question:"The Mach model of Page fault handling with an external pager includes *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"All of the other choices","An external pager running in user space","A low-level MMU handler","A page fault handler that is part of the kernel"]
},{
numb: 164, 
question:"Which of the following information bits in the entry of page table is used to indicate that page is changed since it was loaded in memory? *", 
answer: "Modified bit",
options: [
"Modified bit","Status bit","Present/absent bit","Referenced bit"]
},{
numb: 165, 
question:"Which strategy is a simplest design for speeding up Paging? *", 
answer: "Page table is loaded into registers",
options: [
"Page table is loaded into TLB","Page table is loaded into main memory","Page table is loaded into registers","Page table is loaded into disk"]
},{
numb: 166, 
question:"How many level of scheduling are used in computer *", 
answer: "3",
options: [
"2","4","3","1"]
},{
numb: 167, 
question:"If there are 256 pages and the page size is 4K words, what is the length of logical address? *", 
answer: "20 bits",
options: [
"20 bits","14 bits","17 bits","15 bits"]
},{
numb: 168, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about hard links? *", 
answer: "Hard links can point to files in the network",
options: [
"Hard links require to increase the link count in the i-node for each linking","Hard links can point to files in the network","Hard links do not require extra disk space","Hard links can only point to files on the same machines"]
},{
numb: 169, 
question:"____ is a specialized WRITE command for existing data files that allows for adding records to end of the file. *", 
answer: "APPEND",
options: [
"UPDATE","REWRITE","APPEND","MODIFY"]
},{
numb: 170, 
question:"Which of the following is correct about symbolic links? *", 
answer: "Symbolic links can point to files in the network",
options: [
"Symbolic links need not space to store the name and the file pointed to","Symbolic links can only point to files on the same machines","Symbolic links can point to files in the network","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 171, 
question:"The primary disadvantage of contiguous storage is that ____. *", 
answer: "File can't be expanded unless there is empty space available immediately following it",
options: [
"It is difficult to find information in files","It is hard to implement and manage","File can't be expanded unless there is empty space available immediately following it","It is an inefficient use of space"]
},{
numb: 172, 
question:"Which solution is used to solve the 'missing block' problem in file system consistency? *", 
answer: "The file system checker adds the missing blocks to the free list",
options: [
"The file system checker adds the missing blocks to the free list","The file system checker rebuilds the free list","The file system checker allocate the free block, then copy the duplicate block in used to there","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 173, 
question:"A ____ is a group of related records that contains information to be used by specific application programs to generate reports. *", 
answer: "File",
options: [
"Record group","Field","Directory","File"]
},{
numb: 174, 
question:"A directory in UNIX/Linux consists of the following *", 
answer: "Inode number and file name",
options: [
"None of the other choices","File name, file size, location of the file on disk, date created, owner ID","Inode number and file name","File name, file size, location of the file on disk"]
},{
numb: 175, 
question:"Which of the following is not a well-known technique for organizing the physical storage blocks for a file? *", 
answer: "Sparse block allocation",
options: [
"Contiguous block allocation","Linked list block allocation","Sparse block allocation","Indexed block allocation"]
},{
numb: 176, 
question:"____ allocation allows files to use any storage space available on the disk. *", 
answer: "Noncontiguous storage",
options: [
"Noncontiguous storage","Add-on storage","Contiguous storage","Fragmented storage"]
},{
numb: 177, 
question:"What is incorrect about contiguous allocation of files? *", 
answer: "It does not cause disk fragmentation",
options: [
"It leads to excellent read performance","It is simple to implement","It is widely used on CD-ROMs","It does not cause disk fragmentation"]
},{
numb: 178, 
question:"Which of the following is not file structure? *", 
answer: "Ring",
options: [
"Byte sequence","Record sequence","Ring","Tree"]
},{
numb: 179, 
question:"____ is a specialized WRITE command for existing data files that allows for appending records or for rewriting selected records in their original place in the file. *", 
answer: "MODIFY",
options: [
"REWRITE","UPDATE","APPEND","MODIFY"]
},{
numb: 180, 
question:"How many is maximum number of partition that most disk can be divided up into? *", 
answer: "4",
options: [
"4","3","5","2"]
},{
numb: 181, 
question:"The disk block in a partition that includes a magic number, the number of blocks in the file system and other key administrative information is called: *", 
answer: "Superblock",
options: [
"Superblock","MBR","Free block","Boot block"]
},{
numb: 182, 
question:"Which of the following is not special file? *", 
answer: "Stream special file",
options: [
"Block special file","Character special file","None of the other choices","Stream special file"]
},{
numb: 183, 
question:"Which of the following is true about the block size in disk space management *", 
answer: "the larger the block size is the worse the disk space utilization is",
options: [
"the larger the block size is the worse the disk space utilization is","the larger the block size is the lower the data rate is","the larger the block size is lesser the disk space is","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 184, 
question:"The absolute pathname of a file in Linux is with respect to the *", 
answer: "Root directory on the system",
options: [
"Login directory","Root directory on the system","Home directory","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 185, 
question:"Which is the maximum partition size, if the FAT type is FAT-16 and the block size is 2 KB? *", 
answer: "128 MB",
options: [
"256 MB","512 MB","8 MB","128 MB"]
},{
numb: 186, 
question:"Which of a system callI is to allow the file to appear in more than one directory? *", 
answer: "LINK",
options: [
"OPEN","CREATE","LINK","SEEK"]
},{
numb: 187, 
question:"____ are special files with listings of filenames and their attributes. *", 
answer: "Directories",
options: [
"Databases","Programs","Data files","Directories"]
},{
numb: 188, 
question:"How large is the block size, if the maximum partition size is 128 MB and the FAT type is FAT-16? *", 
answer: "2 KB",
options: [
"8 KB","2 KB","1 KB","4 KB"]
},{
numb: 189, 
question:"The disk blocks in a partition that contains the top of the file system tree is called: *", 
answer: "Root directory",
options: [
"Free space management blocks","Superblock","Root directory","Boot block"]
},{
numb: 190, 
question:"The special files are: *", 
answer: "character special file and block special file",
options: [
"none of the other choices","character special file and block special file","character special file","block special file"]
},{
numb: 191, 
question:"Which of a system callI is to allow the system free up internal table space? *", 
answer: "CLOSE",
options: [
"OPEN","DELETE","SEEK","CLOSE"]
},{
numb: 192, 
question:"Which method is used to implement files to keep each file as a linked list of disk blocks? *", 
answer: "Linked List Allocation",
options: [
"File Allocation Table","Linked List Allocation","i-node","Contiguous Allocation"]
},{
numb: 193, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about hard links and symbolic links? *", 
answer: "Hard links can point to files on other machines",
options: [
"Hard links can point to files on other machines","Hard links do not require extra disk space","Symbolic links need space to store the name and the file pointed to","Symbolic links can point to files in the network"]
},{
numb: 194, 
question:"Which are allocation methods of disk blocks for files: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Contiguous allocation","All of the other choices","Indexed allocation","Linked allocation"]
},{
numb: 195, 
question:"How large is the block size, if the maximum partition size is 8 MB and the FAT type is FAT-12? *", 
answer: "2 KB",
options: [
"1 KB","8 KB","2 KB","4 KB"]
},{
numb: 196, 
question:"Increasing file system performance is implemented by _____ *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Block Read Ahead","All of the other choices","Defragmenting Disks","Buffer cache"]
},{
numb: 197, 
question:"Which of a system callI is to allow the system fetch the attributes and list of disk addresses into main memory for rapid access on later call? *", 
answer: "OPEN",
options: [
"RENAME","CLOSE","OPEN","SEEK"]
},{
numb: 198, 
question:"The File Manager writes the volume name and other descriptive information on an easy-to-access place on each unit: ____ of the magnetic disk *", 
answer: "the outermost part",
options: [
"the innermost part","the outermost part","stored at the beginning of the volume","immediately following the master file directory"]
},{
numb: 199, 
question:"Strategy used for dumping a disk to tapes is: *", 
answer: "Physical dump and Logical dump",
options: [
"Physical dump and Logical dump","Physical dump","None of the other choices","Logical dump"]
},{
numb: 200, 
question:"Which of the following information contain in the entry of the partition tables ? *", 
answer: "Starting and ending address of each partition and Marking a partittion as active",
options: [
"Starting and ending address of each partition","None of the other choices","Marking a partittion as active","Starting and ending address of each partition and Marking a partittion as active"]
},{
numb: 201, 
question:"Disk can be divided up into one or more partitions the first block of every partition is called: *", 
answer: "Boot block",
options: [
"MBR","Free block","Super block","Boot block"]
},{
numb: 202, 
question:"Which of the following is specified to indicate the directory where the file is located? *", 
answer: "Path name",
options: [
"Sub-directory","Extension","Path name","Root directory"]
},{
numb: 203, 
question:"File is generally defined to be: *", 
answer: "A collection of similar records",
options: [
"A collection of related fields","A basic element of data","A collection of similar records","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 204, 
question:"The Linking technique that allows the file to appear in more than one directory are: *", 
answer: "Hard link and Symbolic link",
options: [
"Hard link","Symbolic link","Hard link and Symbolic link","Soft link"]
},{
numb: 205, 
question:"Which of a system callI is to allow the system announce that the file is coming and set some of the attributes? *", 
answer: "CREATE",
options: [
"RENAME","CREATE","CLOSE","OPEN"]
},{
numb: 206, 
question:"Which is the maximum partition size, if the FAT type is FAT-32 and the block size is 4 KB? *", 
answer: "1 TB",
options: [
"1 TB","1 GB","16GB","16 TB"]
},{
numb: 207, 
question:"Which of a system callI is to allow the system to specify from where to take the data in file? *", 
answer: "SEEK",
options: [
"OPEN","CREATE","SEEK","LINK"]
},{
numb: 208, 
question:"Which is the maximum partition size, if FAT type is FAT-12 and the block size is 2 KB? *", 
answer: "8 MB",
options: [
"8 MB","128 MB","256 MB","512 MB"]
},{
numb: 209, 
question:"Operating system MS-DOS is implemented in which of the following allocation methods? *", 
answer: "Linked allocation using FAT",
options: [
"Linked allocation using FAT","Linked allocation","Contiguous allocation","Indexed allocation"]
},{
numb: 210, 
question:"Which of the following is true about the data rate for disk management? *", 
answer: "the larger the block size is the faster the data rate is",
options: [
"the larger the block size is lesser the disk space is","the larger the block size is the lower the data rate is","None of the other choices","the larger the block size is the faster the data rate is"]
},{
numb: 211, 
question:"Which ways are used to keep track of free block in disk space management? *", 
answer: "A linked list method and bitmap method",
options: [
"A bitmap method","A linked list method and bitmap method","None of the other choices","A linked list method"]
},{
numb: 212, 
question:"A table in main memory storing linked list allocation of disk blocks is called: *", 
answer: "File allocation table",
options: [
"Linked list table","File list table","Disk allocation table","File allocation table"]
},{
numb: 213, 
question:"Many computer users and some operating systems call subdirectories ____. *", 
answer: "Folders",
options: [
"Folders","Volumes","Files","Databases"]
},{
numb: 214, 
question:"Which of a system calI is to allow the system free up disk space? *", 
answer: "DELETE",
options: [
"OPEN","CLOSE","SEEK","DELETE"]
},{
numb: 215, 
question:"File Structure can be: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Record sequence","All of the other choices","Tree","Byte sequence"]
},{
numb: 216, 
question:"The Joliet Extensions provide ________ *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Long file name is supported Unicode character","Directory nesting deeper than 8 levels","All of the other choices","Directory names with extensions"]
},{
numb: 217, 
question:"Which part of a disk is used to boot the computer? *", 
answer: "MBR",
options: [
"MBR","Root block","Super block","Free block"]
},{
numb: 218, 
question:"The i-nodes are used in which of the following allocation methods? *", 
answer: "Indexed allocation",
options: [
"Linked allocation using FAT","Contiguous allocation","Linked allocation","Indexed allocation"]
},{
numb: 219, 
question:"Which mechanism is implemented by writing to the log file in file system management and optimization? *", 
answer: "Journaling File Systems",
options: [
"Journaling File Systems","None of the other choices","Virtual File Systems","Log-Structured File Systems"]
},{
numb: 220, 
question:"As long as users refer to files in the ____ directory, they can access their files without entering the complete name from the highest level to the lowest. *", 
answer: "Working",
options: [
"Default","Working","Root","Home"]
},{
numb: 221, 
question:"The File Manager writes the volume name and other descriptive information on an easy-to-access place on each unit: ____ of the CD or DVD *", 
answer: "the innermost part",
options: [
"stored at the beginning of the volume","the innermost part","the outermost part","immediately following the master file directory"]
},{
numb: 222, 
question:"A UNIX or Linux system might identify a file as: //usr//imfst//flynn//inventory.doc. What represents the root directory is ____. *", 
answer: "/",
options: [
"/","flynn","usr","imfst"]
},{
numb: 223, 
question:"Which of the following actions generates an external interrupt? *", 
answer: "An input/output operation is completed.",
options: [
"An input/output operation is completed.","A page that does not exist in the main memory is accessed by the virtual storage management.","A system call instruction is executed.","Division by zero occurs."]
},{
numb: 224, 
question:"A operation concerning Stable Storage is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Crash recovery","All of the other choices","Stable writes","Stable reads"]
},{
numb: 225, 
question:"When an external device becomes ready to be serviced by the processor, the device sends this signal to the processor. This signal is called: *", 
answer: "Interrupt signal",
options: [
"Handler signal","Halt signal","None of the other choices","Interrupt signal"]
},{
numb: 226, 
question:"What's asynchronous transfer in principles of I/O software? *", 
answer: "The CPU starts the transfer and goes off to do something else until the interrupt arrives",
options: [
"1/1","The CPU starts the transfer and goes off to do something else until the interrupt arrives","","The user program starts system call to transfer and automatically suspended until the data are available in the buffer"]
},{
numb: 227, 
question:"A computer uses a programmable clock in square-wave mode. If 500 MHz crystal is used, what should be the value of the holding register to achieve a clock resolution of 1 msec (clock tick)? *", 
answer: "500,000",
options: [
"5,000,000","50,000,000","50,000","500,000"]
},{
numb: 228, 
question:"Which class of I/O devices that Scanner belong to? *", 
answer: "Character devices",
options: [
"1/1","Stream devices","Character devices",""]
},{
numb: 229, 
question:"An example of a I/O character devices is *", 
answer: "Modem",
options: [
"All of the other choices","Modem","Disks","CD ROM"]
},{
numb: 230, 
question:"Which of the following statements about device drivers is incorrect? *", 
answer: "In the I/O software architecture, the device drivers layer lie right above the hardward, and below the interrupt handlers layer",
options: [
"In the I/O software architecture, the device drivers layer lie right above the hardward, and below the interrupt handlers layer","None of the other choices","Most operating systems expect device drivers to be part of the kernel","A device driver is a set of device-specific code for controlling the I/O device attached to a computer"]
},{
numb: 231, 
question:"Which class of I/O devices that keyboard belong to? *", 
answer: "Character devices",
options: [
"Character devices","Stream devices","Block devices","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 232, 
question:"Which is the right order between the 4 I/O software layers? *", 
answer: "User-level I/O software, Device-independent OS software, Device drivers, Interrupt handlers",
options: [
"User-level I/O software, Device drivers, Interrupt handlers, Device-independent OS software","Device-independent OS software, user-level I/O software, Device drivers, Interrupt handlers","User-level I/O software, Interrupt handlers, Device drivers, Device-independent OS software","User-level I/O software, Device-independent OS software, Device drivers, Interrupt handlers"]
},{
numb: 233, 
question:"Which of the following statements is not correct about 'device independence'? *", 
answer: "Device independence requires all programmers to deal with different devices directly",
options: [
"Files and devices are accessed in the same way, independent of their physical nature","Device independent interfaces should be given to programmers","A system has to maintain only one set of system calls for both writing on a file and writing on the console","Device independence requires all programmers to deal with different devices directly"]
},{
numb: 234, 
question:"Programmed I/O should be acceptable for which of the following systems? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"Embedded systems","Interactive systems","Multiprogramming systems","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 235, 
question:"Which of the following I/O software is done by Device drivers? *", 
answer: "Writing commands to the device registers",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Writing commands to the device registers","Converting binary integers to ASCII for printing","Checking to see if the user is permitted to use the device"]
},{
numb: 236, 
question:"Imagine that a certain printer can print 400 characters per second and that the time to write a character to the printer's output register is so short it can be ignored. If to run this printer using interrupt-driven I/O and each character printed requires an interrupt that takes 50 µsec all-in to service. How many percent of the CPU does the interrupt overhead cost? *", 
answer: "2% of the CPU",
options: [
"98% of the CPU","4% of the CPU","2% of the CPU","96% of the CPU"]
},{
numb: 237, 
question:"Which of the following I/O software is done by Device-independent OS software *", 
answer: "Checking to see if the user is permitted to use the device",
options: [
"Checking to see if the user is permitted to use the device","Computing the track, sector, and head for a disk read","Writing commands to the device registers","Converting binary integers to ASCII for printing"]
},{
numb: 238, 
question:"Which of the following statements about the task of device controller of I/O devices is correct ? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Make available to main memory","All of the other choices","Perform error correction as necessary","Convert serial bit stream to block of bytes"]
},{
numb: 239, 
question:"The term _____ characterizes a system configuration that includes an I/O module that is a separate processor with a specialized instruction set. *", 
answer: "DMA",
options: [
"Programmed I/O","None of the other choices","DMA","I/O device"]
},{
numb: 240, 
question:"Imagine that a certain printer can print 400 characters per second and that the time to write a character to the printer's output register is so short it can be ignored. If to run this printer using interrupt-driven I/O and each character printed requires an interrupt that takes 50 µsec all-in to service. How many percent of the CPU is available to do other work? *", 
answer: "98% of the CPU",
options: [
"98% of the CPU","96% of the CPU","2% of the CPU","4% of the CPU"]
},{
numb: 241, 
question:"In separating I/O and memory space system, the set of I/O ports form the 'I/O port space'. This mechanism allows: *", 
answer: "Only programs in kernel can access to I/O devices",
options: [
"Both progams in user space and kernel can access to I/O devices","None of the other choices","Only programs in kernel can access to I/O devices","Programs in user space can easily access to I/O devices"]
},{
numb: 242, 
question:"Which approach is used in order to CPU communicate with the control registers of the I/O device? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Memory-mapped I/O","Separating I/O and memory space","All of the other choices","Hybrid: separating I/O and memory space and memory-mapped I/O"]
},{
numb: 243, 
question:"Which of the following statements is not correct about the device controller of I/O devices? *", 
answer: "Is software component of device",
options: [
"Is electronic component of device","Is software component of device","Can handle two, four, or even eight identical devices","Is also called adapter"]
},{
numb: 244, 
question:"Imagine that a certain modem can read 7,000 characters per second and that the time to read a character to the modem register is so short it can be ignored. If to run this modem using interrupt-driven I/O and each character read requires an interrupt that takes 10 µsec all-in to service. How many percent of the CPU does the interrupt overhead cost? *", 
answer: "7% of the CPU",
options: [
"93% of the CPU","4% of the CPU","7% of the CPU","96% of the CPU"]
},{
numb: 245, 
question:"Rearrange the layers in I/O software starting at the bottom: 1. User-level I/O software; 2. Device drivers3; Interrupt handlers; 4. Hardware5; Device-independent OS software. *", 
answer: "43251",
options: [
"43251","12345","15234","54321"]
},{
numb: 246, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect? *", 
answer: "A hard drive is an example of a I/O character device",
options: [
"A hard drive is an example of a I/O character device","In the interrupt-driven I/O technique, the processor issues an I/O request, continues with other work and eventually receives notification that the request was fulfilled","The term data rate refers to the speed with which data moves to and from the individual I/O device","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 247, 
question:"Which of the following statement is not true about separating I/O and memory space? *", 
answer: "Caching a device control register would be disastrous",
options: [
"Programs must use 2 instructions to test whether the device is ready","There is special protection mechanism to keep user processes from performing I/O","Caching a device control register would be disastrous","Device drivers must be written using assembly language"]
},{
numb: 248, 
question:"In order that CPU communicates with the comtrol registers in the devices, the control register is assigned: *", 
answer: "I/O port number",
options: [
"Index","I/O address","I/O port number","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 249, 
question:"An example of a I/O block devices is *", 
answer: "CD ROM",
options: [
"All of the other choices","CD ROM","Modem","Printer"]
},{
numb: 250, 
question:"Which class of I/O devices that Clock belong to? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"Stream devices","Block devices","Character devices","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 251, 
question:"Which of the following statements about interrupts and trap instructions is incorrect? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"A trap instruction is a software-generated interrupt","None of the other choices","An interrupt is a hardware-generated change of control flow within the system","An interrupt handler deals with the cause of the interrupt"]
},{
numb: 252, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about the main classes of I/O devices? *", 
answer: "Stream devices",
options: [
"Block devices and Character devices","Block devices","Character devices","Stream devices"]
},{
numb: 253, 
question:"DMA operations require the following information from the processor *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Number of words to be read or written","Address of I/O device","Starting memory location to read from and write to","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 254, 
question:"In general, which is the best technique for I/O Data transfer? *", 
answer: "Direct Memory Access",
options: [
"Direct Memory Access","Programmed I/O","Interrupt-Driven I/O","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 255, 
question:"Assuming that it takes 10 nsec to copy a byte, how much time, does it take to completely rewrite the screen of a 200 character x 20 line text mode memory-mapped screen? *", 
answer: "40 micro-sec",
options: [
"10 micro-sec","40 micro-sec","20 micro-sec","30 micro-sec"]
},{
numb: 256, 
question:"The main classes of I/O devices are? *", 
answer: "Block devices and Character devices",
options: [
"Block devices and Character devices","Character devices","Block devices","Stream devices"]
},{
numb: 257, 
question:"Which mechanism is described as 'the device controller sneaks in and steals an occasional bus cycle from the CPU once in a while, delaying it slightly'? *", 
answer: "Cycle stealing",
options: [
"All of the others","Cycle stealing","Cycle sneaking","Interrupt stealing"]
},{
numb: 258, 
question:"In the hierarchical structure for managing I/O, which layer is closest to the hardware? *", 
answer: "Interrupt handlers",
options: [
"Device-independent OS software","None of the other choices","Interrupt handlers","Device drivers"]
},{
numb: 259, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about I/O using DMA? *", 
answer: "DMA is software solution to speed up data transfer between I/O device and memory",
options: [
"DMA is software solution to speed up data transfer between I/O device and memory","DMA helps reduce the number of interrupts","DMA helps free up the CPU during the I/O to do other work","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 260, 
question:"Which of the following statements about device drivers is correct? *", 
answer: "Device drivers layer lies right above the interrupt handlers layer and below the device-independent OS software layer",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Device drivers lie on top of I/O software layer architecture","Device drivers layer lies right above the interrupt handlers layer and below the device-independent OS software layer","Device drivers lie on bottom of I/O software layer architecture"]
},{
numb: 261, 
question:"Device Driver is normally written by: *", 
answer: "Device's Manufacturer",
options: [
"All of the other choices","Computer's Manufacturer","OS's Manufacturer","Device's Manufacturer"]
},{
numb: 262, 
question:"How much cylinder skew is needed for a 3600- RPM (rotate per minute) disk with the track-to-track seek time of 1 msec? The disk has 200 sectors of 512 bytes on each track. *", 
answer: "12 sectors",
options: [
"24 sectors","18 sectors","36 sectors","12 sectors"]
},{
numb: 263, 
question:"Which of the following statements is not correct about DMA ? *", 
answer: "DMA controller is usually faster than CPU",
options: [
"DMA helps reduce the number of interrupts (in comparison with interrupt-driven I/O)","DMA controller has access to the system bus independent of the CPU","The operating system can only use DMA if the hardware has a DMA controller","DMA controller is usually faster than CPU"]
},{
numb: 264, 
question:"What is the table where its entry contains the memory address of Interrupt service routine *", 
answer: "Interrupt vector table",
options: [
"Address table","Address lines table","Interrupt vector table","Interrupt table"]
},{
numb: 265, 
question:"Each device attached to your computer comes with a special program called a __________ that facilitates the communication between the device and the OS. *", 
answer: "device driver",
options: [
"device driver","communication utility","device configurator","translator"]
},{
numb: 266, 
question:"Which of the following statements about interrupts and system calls is incorrect? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"Interrupts are caused by external events","Interrupts are asynchronous","System calls are caused by internal (synchronous) events","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 267, 
question:"Imagine that a certain modem can read 7,000 characters per second and that the time to read a character to the modem register is so short it can be ignored. If to run this modem using interrupt-driven I/O and each character read requires an interrupt that takes 10 µsec all-in to service. How many percent of the CPU is available to do other work? *", 
answer: "93% of the CPU",
options: [
"7% of the CPU","93% of the CPU","96% of the CPU","4% of the CPU"]
},{
numb: 268, 
question:"Assuming that it takes 10 nsec to copy a byte, how much time, does it take to completely rewrite the screen of an 80 character x 25 line text mode memory-mapped screen? *", 
answer: "20 micro-sec",
options: [
"20 micro-sec","30 micro-sec","10 micro-sec","40 micro-sec"]
},{
numb: 269, 
question:"Which of the following statement is correct about a disadvantage of memory-mapped I/O? *", 
answer: "Caching a device control register would be disastrous",
options: [
"Programs can use 1 instruction to test whether the device is ready","No special protection mechanism needed to keep user processes from performing I/O","Since the control registers of devices are mapped into the memory space, device drivers can be written in C","Caching a device control register would be disastrous"]
},{
numb: 270, 
question:"How many categories can be the I/O devices roughly divided into? *", 
answer: "2",
options: [
"1","2","3","4"]
},{
numb: 271, 
question:"Which class of I/O devices that disks and tapes belong to? *", 
answer: "Block devices",
options: [
"Block devices","Stream devices","Character devices","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 272, 
question:"Which statement about DMA is incorrect? *", 
answer: "It is always true that DMA is less expensive than CPU-mediate data transfers",
options: [
"The CPU can start a DMA block transfer, and in the mean time do other work","The controller does not need to wait for the CPU to transfer data to/from memory","The CPU needs not to be concerned with the time it takes to transfer data","It is always true that DMA is less expensive than CPU-mediate data transfers"]
},{
numb: 273, 
question:"The I/O technique where the processor busy waits for an I/O operation to complete is called: *", 
answer: "Programmed I/O",
options: [
"Direct Memory Access (DMA)","Programmed I/O","Interrupt-driven I/O","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 274, 
question:"In the memory-mapped I/O system, in order that CPU communicates with the comtrol registers in the devices, the control register is assigned: *", 
answer: "Unique memory address",
options: [
"Unique memory address","I/O address","Index","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 275, 
question:"An example of the key differences that can exist across (and even in) types of I/O devices is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Error conditions","Data representation","Data rate","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 276, 
question:"An interrupt that leaves the machine in well-defined state is called a(n) ______ *", 
answer: "Precise interrupt",
options: [
"Precise interrupt","Disappointed interrupt","Imprecise interrupt","Required interrupt"]
},{
numb: 277, 
question:"Which of the following I/O software is done by User-level software *", 
answer: "Converting binary integers to ASCII for printing",
options: [
"Computing the track, sector, and head for a disk read","Writing commands to the device registers","Converting binary integers to ASCII for printing","Checking to see if the user is permitted to use the device"]
},{
numb: 278, 
question:"What is the correct approach with requesting the dedicated devices to solve deadlock using Ostrich algorithm?", 
answer: "The device driver decides blocking and returning an error code",
options: [
"The device driver decides blocking and returning an error code","The device driver kills those requesting processes","The device driver stops the current jobs and releases the devices","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 279, 
question:"A simplest way to break a deadlock is to *", 
answer: "kill one of the processes",
options: [
"kill one of the processes","rollback","lock one of the processes","preempt a resource"]
},{
numb: 280, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does Request all resources initially attack? *", 
answer: "Hold and wait",
options: [
"No preemption","Circular-wait condition","Mutual exclusion","Hold and wait"]
},{
numb: 281, 
question:"The permanent blocking of a set of processes that compete for system resources is called *", 
answer: "Deadlock",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Starvation","Prioritization","Deadlock"]
},{
numb: 282, 
question:"If in a resource-allocation graph, each resource type has exactly one instance, which of the following indicate a deadlock situation? *", 
answer: "The graph has at least one cycle.",
options: [
"The graph has no cycle.","The graph is not connected.","The graph has at least one cycle.","The graph is connected."]
},{
numb: 283, 
question:"____ is when, in modern printing systems, a disk accepts output from several Deadlock occurs on a modern printer when ____. *", 
answer: "The printer needs all of a job's output before it will begin printing, but the spooling system fills the available disk space with only partially completed output.",
options: [
"The network connection for the printer overflows with too many requests to use the printer.","The buffer fills up with too many print jobs and the printer cannot decide which one to print.","Too many users attempt to access the printer at the same time.","The printer needs all of a job's output before it will begin printing, but the spooling system fills the available disk space with only partially completed output."]
},{
numb: 284, 
question:"Which of the following is not a condition necessary for deadlock to exist? *", 
answer: "Preemption condition",
options: [
"Circular-wait condition","Hold and wait condition","Preemption condition","Mutual-exclusion condition"]
},{
numb: 285, 
question:"For matrix-based algorithm to detect deadlock, total number of instances of each resource is given by: *", 
answer: "Existing resource vector",
options: [
"Existing resource vector","Request matrix","Available resource vector","Current allocation matrix"]
},{
numb: 286, 
question:"What is the way to recover from a deadlock: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Rollback","Killing processes","All of the other choices","Preempt a resource"]
},{
numb: 287, 
question:"What's true about preemptable resources? *", 
answer: "Can be taken away from a process with no ill effects",
options: [
"Will cause the process to fail if taken away","Can be taken away from a process with no ill effects","Can share among processes","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 288, 
question:"For matrix-based algorithm to detect deadlock, number of instances of each resource each process needs is given by *", 
answer: "Request matrix",
options: [
"Request matrix","Available resource vector","Existing resource vector","Current allocation matrix"]
},{
numb: 289, 
question:"Deadlock definition: 'A set of processes is deadlocked if each process in the set is waiting for an event that only another process in the set can cause.' What does event mean? *", 
answer: "The event is release of a currently held resource",
options: [
"None of the other choices","The event is press some key on keyboard","The event is release of a currently held resource","The event is some mouse click"]
},{
numb: 290, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does order resources numerically attack? *", 
answer: "Circular-wait condition",
options: [
"Circular-wait condition","Hold and wait","No preemption","Mutual exclusion"]
},{
numb: 291, 
question:"For matrix-based algorithm to detect deadlock, number of instances of each resource each process currently holds is given by: *", 
answer: "Current allocation matrix",
options: [
"Available resource vector","Existing resource vector","Request matrix","Current allocation matrix"]
},{
numb: 292, 
question:"An example of preemptable resources is *", 
answer: "Memory",
options: [
"Memory","CD-ROM device","None of the other choices","DVD device"]
},{
numb: 293, 
question:"____ is when each process involved in the impasse is waiting for another to voluntarily release the resource so that at least one will be able to continue on. *", 
answer: "Circular-wait condition",
options: [
"Mutual-exclusion condition","No preemption condition","Hold and wait condition","Circular-wait condition"]
},{
numb: 294, 
question:"Failure to lock database records before updating them may result in a ____ between processes *", 
answer: "Race",
options: [
"Race","Struggle","Livelock","Deadlock"]
},{
numb: 295, 
question:"In a directed graph used to model deadlock, resources are represented using *", 
answer: "Square",
options: [
"Ellipse","Circular","Square","Rectangle"]
},{
numb: 296, 
question:"An algorithm designed to detect starvation by tracking how long each job has been waiting for resources is the same concept as ____. *", 
answer: "Aging",
options: [
"Aging","Deadlock","Preemption","Round robin"]
},{
numb: 297, 
question:"What is the correct approach with the Mutual Exclusion condition to prevent Deadlock? *", 
answer: "Spool everything",
options: [
"Request all resources initially","Order resources numerically","Spool everything","Take resources away"]
},{
numb: 298, 
question:"Each of the following characteristics applies to deadlock avoidance except *", 
answer: "Widely used in modern operating systems",
options: [
"Relying on ability to predict effect of satisfying resource allocation requests","Inherently conservative strategy","Widely used in modern operating systems","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 299, 
question:"What's true about non-preemptable resources? *", 
answer: "Will cause the process to fail if taken away",
options: [
"Can be taken away from a process with no ill effects","None of the other choices","Will cause the process to fail if taken away","Can share among processes"]
},{
numb: 300, 
question:"____ allows a resource to be held by a process as long as it is needed.. *", 
answer: "No preemption condition",
options: [
"No preemption condition","Circular-wait condition","Mutual-exclusion condition","Hold and wait condition"]
},{
numb: 301, 
question:"A system is said to be in an unsafe state if *", 
answer: "The operating system cannot guarantee that all current processes can complete their work",
options: [
"The operating system cannot guarantee that all current processes can complete their work","None of the other choices","A process is indefinitely postponed","The system is deadlocked"]
},{
numb: 302, 
question:"What is the correct approach with the hold and wait condition to prevent Deadlock? *", 
answer: "Request all resources initially",
options: [
"Take resources away","Spool everything","Request all resources initially","Order resources numerically"]
},{
numb: 303, 
question:"In a directed graph used to model deadlock, processes are represented using *", 
answer: "Circular",
options: [
"Rectangle","Circular","Ellipse","Square"]
},{
numb: 304, 
question:"All deadlocks involve conflicting needs for resources by *", 
answer: "Two or more processes",
options: [
"Three or more processes","None of the other choices","Two or more processes","One or more processes"]
},{
numb: 305, 
question:"Dijkstra's Banker's Algorithm require the system to maintain the resource information for each process, including: *", 
answer: "d. The maximum resources that can be requested and The number of resources currently acquired by the process",
options: [
"a. The maximum resources that can be requested by the process","b. The number of resources currently acquired by the process","c. A count of the system's total resources","d. The maximum resources that can be requested and The number of resources currently acquired by the process"]
},{
numb: 306, 
question:"What is the weakness of the Banker's algorithm? *", 
answer: "Requiring that processes state their maximum needs in advance",
options: [
"Enabling the number of resources to fluctuate","Enabling processes to hold their resources indefinitely","Requiring that processes state their maximum needs in advance","Allowing the population of processes to vary over time"]
},{
numb: 307, 
question:"If a system is deadlocked, no processes can *", 
answer: "all of the other choices",
options: [
"release resources","be awakened","run","all of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 308, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does take resources away attack? *", 
answer: "No preemption",
options: [
"Circular-wait condition","Hold and wait","Mutual exclusion","No preemption"]
},{
numb: 309, 
question:"Which method is used to prevent the communication deadlock? *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Timeouts","Acknowledge signal","Handling alarm","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 310, 
question:"For matrix-based algorithm to detect deadlock, number of instances of resource currently unassigned is given by: *", 
answer: "Available resource vector",
options: [
"Available resource vector","Request matrix","Current allocation matrix","Existing resource vector"]
},{
numb: 311, 
question:"In a directed graph used to model deadlock, ____ represents deadlock. *", 
answer: "Cycle",
options: [
"Cycle","Dashed arrow","Solid arrow","Any path"]
},{
numb: 312, 
question:"What is the correct approach with the No preemption condition to prevent Deadlock? *", 
answer: "Take resources away",
options: [
"Order resources numerically","Spool everything","Request all resources initially","Take resources away"]
},{
numb: 313, 
question:"A possibility of deadlock can occur: *", 
answer: "If a system is in unsafe state",
options: [
"If a system is in safe state","If a system is in unsafe state","If a system is in instable state","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 314, 
question:"____ is when, in modern printing systems, a disk accepts output from several users and acts as a temporary storage area for all output until the printer is ready to accept it *", 
answer: "Spooling",
options: [
"Spooling","Buffering","Lagging","Spoofing"]
},{
numb: 315, 
question:"The first and simplest recovery method, and the most drastic, is to ____. *", 
answer: "Terminate every job that's active in the system and restart them from the beginning",
options: [
"Select a nondeadlocked job, preempt the resources it's holding, and allocate them to a Deadlocked process so it can resume execution, thus breaking the deadlock","Terminate every job that's active in the system and restart them from the beginning","Identify which jobs are involved in the deadlock and terminate them one at a time, checking to see if the deadlock is eliminated after each removal","Terminate only the jobs involved in the deadlock and ask their users to resubmit them"]
},{
numb: 316, 
question:"Which of the following statements does not apply to manual deadlock management? *", 
answer: "OS designers are normally very sensitive to deadlock when designing resource managers",
options: [
"Recovery may involves rebooting the system","Deadlock is relatively infrequent for some system resources","OS designers are normally very sensitive to deadlock when designing resource managers","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 317, 
question:"One of way to prevent a deadlock is ________ *", 
answer: "Spool everything",
options: [
"Locks one of the processes","Spool everything","Kills one of the processes","Rollback"]
},{
numb: 318, 
question:"____ occurs when two processes do not release control of resources they are using. *", 
answer: "Hold and wait condition",
options: [
"Hold and wait condition","Circular-wait condition","Mutual-exclusion condition","No preemption condition"]
},{
numb: 319, 
question:"A simplest way to break a deadlock is to *", 
answer: "Kills one of the processes",
options: [
"Locks one of the processes","Kills one of the processes","Rollback","Preempt a resource"]
},{
numb: 320, 
question:"____ is the act of allowing only one process to have access to a dedicated resource. *", 
answer: "Mutual-exclusion condition",
options: [
"No preemption condition","Mutual-exclusion condition","Hold and wait condition","Circular-wait condition"]
},{
numb: 321, 
question:"Sequence of events required to use a resource is *", 
answer: "Request the resource, Use the resource, Release the resource",
options: [
"Use the resource, Release the resource, Request the resource","None of the other choices","Request the resource, Release the resource, Use the resource","Request the resource, Use the resource, Release the resource"]
},{
numb: 322, 
question:"Which strategy is used in the Banker's algorithm for dealing with deadlocks? *", 
answer: "Deadlock avoidance",
options: [
"Deadlock prevention","Deadlock detection","Deadlock avoidance","Deadlock ignorance"]
},{
numb: 323, 
question:"Assume the following events and actions take place: 1. P1 requests and is allocated the printer R1; 2.P1 releases the printer R1; 3. P2 requests and is allocated the disk drive R2; 4. P2 releases the disk R2; 5. P3 requests and is allocated the plotter R3; 6. P3 releases the plotter R3. Which of the following statement is true? *", 
answer: "There is no deadlock",
options: [
"There is no deadlock","Event 5 caused deadlock.","Event 6 caused deadlock.","Event 4 caused deadlock"]
},{
numb: 324, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does spool everything attack? *", 
answer: "Mutual exclusion",
options: [
"Hold and wait","Mutual exclusion","Circular-wait condition","No preemption"]
},{
numb: 325, 
question:"A network that's congested or has filled a large percentage of its I/O buffer space can become deadlocked if it doesn't have ____ to control the flow of messages through the network. *", 
answer: "Protocols",
options: [
"Protocols","Policies","Procedures","Rules"]
},{
numb: 326, 
question:"The scheme of ____ removes the possibility of a circular wait and therefore guarantees the removal of deadlocks. *", 
answer: "Hierarchical ordering",
options: [
"Hierarchical ordering","Preemption","Saving and restoring job state","Requesting all resources before job run"]
},{
numb: 327, 
question:"Typical approaches to handle deadlocks do not include: *", 
answer: "Deterrence",
options: [
"Avoidance","Prevention","Detection","Deterrence"]
},{
numb: 328, 
question:"What is the correct approach with the Circular wait condition to prevent Deadlock? *", 
answer: "Order resources numerically",
options: [
"Take resources away","Request all resources initially","Spool everything","Order resources numerically"]
},{
numb: 329, 
question:"What is not the way to recover from a deadlock: *", 
answer: "Locks one of the processes",
options: [
"Killing processes","Preempt a resource","Locks one of the processes","Rollback"]
},{
numb: 330, 
question:"Which of the following is not a well-known technique for organizing the physical storage blocks for a file?", 
answer: "Sparse block allocation",
options: [
"Indexed block allocation","Contiguous block allocation","Linked list block allocation","Sparse block allocation"]
},{
numb: 331, 
question:"There are ____ entries per page in the Page table.", 
answer: "1",
options: [
"1","2","3","4"]
},{
numb: 332, 
question:"Which of the following information bits used by the various page replacement policies indicates if the page has been called lately?", 
answer: "d. Modified bit",
options: [
"a. Locality bit","b. Status bit","c. Referenced bit","d. Modified bit"]
},{
numb: 333, 
question:"In separating I/O and memory space system, the set of I/O ports form the I/O port space. This mechanism allows:", 
answer: "Both programs in user space and kernel can access to I/O devices",
options: [
"Programs in user space can easily access to I/O devices","Only programs in kernel can access to I/O devices","Both programs in user space and kernel can access to I/O devices","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 334, 
question:"Each of the following characteristics applies to deadlock avoidance except *", 
answer: "B. Relying on ability to predict effect of satisfying resource allocation requests",
options: [
"A. Widely used in modern operating systems","B. Relying on ability to predict effect of satisfying resource allocation requests","C. Inherently conservative strategy","D. None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 335, 
question:"In the memory-mapped I/O system, in order that CPU communicates with the control registers in the devices, the control register is assigned :", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"Index","I/O address","Unique memory address","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 336, 
question:"Which of the following information bits in the entry of page table is used to indicate Page Fault?", 
answer: "Status bit",
options: [
"Present/absent bit","Status bit","Referenced bit","Modified bit"]
},{
numb: 337, 
question:"The page table for each process maintains _________ .", 
answer: "C) the page location for each frame of the process",
options: [
"A) the physical memory location of the process","B) the frame location for each page of the process","C) the page location for each frame of the process","D) the logical memory location of the process"]
},{
numb: 338, 
question:"In separating I/O and memory space system, the set of I/O ports form the I/O port space. This mechanism allows:", 
answer: "B. None of the other choices",
options: [
"A. Programs in user space can easily access to I/O devices","B. None of the other choices","C. Only programs in kernel can access to I/O devices","D. Both programs in user space and kernel can access to I/O devices"]
},{
numb: 339, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about user mode and kernel mode? *", 
answer: "D. In user mode, user program can execute only a subset of instructions",
options: [
"A. In kernel mode, the OS can execute every instruction in the instruction set","B. Having two modes of operation helps prevent user programs from accessing critical instructions","C. None of the other choices","D. In user mode, user program can execute only a subset of instructions"]
},{
numb: 340, 
question:"Assume jobs A-D arrive in quick succession in the READY queue. Using round robin scheduling (quantum=4), the average turnaround time for each job is ____. *", 
answer: "18.25",
options: [
"18.25","5","73","20"]
},{
numb: 341, 
question:"Consider a swapping system in which the memory consists of the following hole sizes: 10 K, 4 K, 20 K, 15 K, 9 K. Assume worst fit algorithm is used. Which holes are taken for successive segment requests of 8 K, 12 K, 10 K? *", 
answer: "20 K, 15 K, left over of 20 K",
options: [
"10 K, 20 K, 15 K","9 K, 15 K, 10 K","20 K, 15 K, left over of 20 K","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 342, 
question:"A computer has four page frames. The time of loading, time of last access, and the R and M bits for each page are as shown below (the times are in clock ticks). Which page will Second Chance replace? *", 
answer: "1",
options: [
"2","3","0","1"]
},{
numb: 343, 
question:"The special files are (choose 1 answer only): *", 
answer: "character special files and block special files",
options: [
"character special file","none of the other choices","block special file","character special files and block special files"]
},{
numb: 344, 
question:"Which strategy is used in the Banker's algorithm for dealing with deadlocks? *", 
answer: "Deadlock avoidance",
options: [
"Deadlock detection","Deadlock ignorance","Deadlock prevention","Deadlock avoidance"]
},{
numb: 345, 
question:"Which of the following synchronization mechanisms does not rely on busy-waiting? *", 
answer: "Semaphores",
options: [
"Lock variables","Strict alternation","Semaphores","Peterson's algorithm"]
},{
numb: 346, 
question:"In a directed graphs model, a possible of deadlock can occur: *", 
answer: "If graph contains a cycle and only one instance per resource type",
options: [
"None of the others","If graph contains a cycle and several instances per resource type","If graph contains a cycle and only one instance per resource type","If graph contains no cycle"]
},{
numb: 347, 
question:"Which of the following statements about segmentation is false? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"The total address space can be more than the size of physical memory","There are several linear address spaces","None of the other choices","Sharing of procedures between different users can be facilitated"]
},{
numb: 348, 
question:"Which of the following conditions of semaphore variable 's' implies a busy critical region? *", 
answer: "s",
options: [
"1 point","s > 0","None of the other choices","s"]
},{
numb: 349, 
question:"Which of the following systems is used in time-critical environments where data must be processed within a strict time limit? *", 
answer: "Real-time",
options: [
"Embedded","Hybrid","Real-time","Interactive"]
},{
numb: 350, 
question:"In which of the following environments preemption is essential? *", 
answer: "Interactive",
options: [
"Interactive","Real time","Batch","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 351, 
question:"All deadlocks involve conflicting needs for resources by *", 
answer: "Two or more processes",
options: [
"Three or more processes","One or more processes","None of the other choices","Two or more processes"]
},{
numb: 352, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about Memory-mapped I/O and Programmed I/O? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Programmed I/O is a way to actually carry out the I/O operations","Programmed I/O may use memory-mapped I/O to fulfill the I/O tasks","Memory-mapped I/O is a way to control the device"]
},{
numb: 353, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about Translation Look-aside Buffer (TLB)? *", 
answer: "The use of TLB eliminates the need for keeping a page table in memory",
options: [
"TLB only maintains a subset of the entries stored in the full memory-based page table","When there is a TLB miss the system needs to access the page table","None of the other choices","The use of TLB eliminates the need for keeping a page table in memory"]
},{
numb: 354, 
question:"Which of the following is not correct about the reliability of different RAID levels? *", 
answer: "There is no reliability support in RAID level 0",
options: [
"In RAID level 2, a single bit error in a word can be detected AND corrected","There is no reliability support in RAID level 0","All RAID levels can survive one disk crash","In RAID levels 3, 4, 5 a single bit error in a word can be detected"]
},{
numb: 355, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about Translation Look-aside Buffer (TLB)? *", 
answer: "c. A TLB miss implies a disk operation will follow",
options: [
"a. A TLB is sometimes known as an associative memory","b. None of the other choices","c. A TLB miss implies a disk operation will follow","d. Each entry of a TLB contains the information about one page, including the virtual page number and the corresponding page frame"]
},{
numb: 356, 
question:"Which of the following statements is incorrect about I/O using DMA?", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"DMA helps reduce the number of interrupts","None of the other choices","In essence, DMA is programmed I/O, except the fact that DMA, instead of the CPU, does all the work","DMA helps free up the CPU during the I/O to do other work"]
},{
numb: 357, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. Their (externally determined) priorities are 3, 5, 2, 1, and 4, respectively, with 5 being the highest priority. Determine the mean process average turnaround time for priority scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead . *", 
answer: "16,8 minutes",
options: [
"10,8 minutes","16,8 minutes","54 minutes","12,8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 358, 
question:"A page fault means that we referenced a page *", 
answer: "c. that was not in main memory",
options: [
"a. with an incorrect I/O request","b. that was outside the memory boundaries","c. that was not in main memory","d. that was not in secondary storage"]
},{
numb: 359, 
question:"Which is a wrong statement about the quantum used in Round Robin algorithm? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"If the quantum is very large, RR is essentially FCFS","None of the other choices","A reasonable value of quantum is around 20-50 ms","If the quantum is very small, the CPU efficiency is reduced"]
},{
numb: 360, 
question:"With paging, when is the internal fragmentation possible? *", 
answer: "The last page of the job is less than the maximum page size",
options: [
"Such thing cannot happen","The last page of the job is less than the maximum page size","Page does not fit the frame","The virtual memory assigned to the program is less than the physical memory assigned to it"]
},{
numb: 361, 
question:"Which of the following is an advantage of Memory-mapped I/O? *", 
answer: "c. Since the control registers of devices are mapped into the memory space, device drivers can be written without using Assembly language",
options: [
"a. Since there is only one address space, all I/O devices must examine all memory references to see which ones to response to","b. None of the other choices","c. Since the control registers of devices are mapped into the memory space, device drivers can be written without using Assembly language","d. Using memory-mapped I/O, caching a device control register is not acceptable"]
},{
numb: 362, 
question:"A(n) _________ is provided to make system calls from some programming languages *", 
answer: "procedure library",
options: [
"procedure library","none of the other choices","pointer","operator"]
},{
numb: 363, 
question:"Which RAID level duplicates all the disks? *", 
answer: "1",
options: [
"4","3","2","1"]
},{
numb: 364, 
question:"Which of the following statements is not correct about Graphic adapter? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Contains a special memory called video RAM","Supports different method of coding pixel color","Supports some number of screen sizes (resolution)"]
},{
numb: 365, 
question:"The methods determine where page is on the disk when it is paged out is *", 
answer: "Both Paging to a static swap area and Backing up pages dynamically",
options: [
"Paging to a static swap area","Both Paging to a static swap area and Backing up pages dynamically","None of the other choices","Backing up pages dynamically"]
},{
numb: 366, 
question:"Which is not a DVD Improvement on CDs to increase the capacity? *", 
answer: "Diameter of disc",
options: [
"Smaller pits","Diameter of disc","A kind laser (red, blue)","A tighter spiral"]
},{
numb: 367, 
question:"Dual-layer, double-sided DVD can hold ____ . *", 
answer: "17 GB",
options: [
"9.4 GB","17 GB","8.5 GB","4.7 GB"]
},{
numb: 368, 
question:"Which FAT type is used, if the maximum partition size is 256 MB and the block size is 4KB? *", 
answer: "FAT-16",
options: [
"FAT-32","FAT-16","None of the other choices","FAT-12"]
},{
numb: 369, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does 'Request all resources initially' attack? *", 
answer: "Hold and wait",
options: [
"Circular-wait condition","Mutual exclusion","No preemption","Hold and wait"]
},{
numb: 370, 
question:"Which of the following is not a task of I/O management of OS? *", 
answer: "Mapping files onto secondary storage",
options: [
"Manage main memory for the devices using caching, buffering, and spooling","Mapping files onto secondary storage","Maintain and provide a general device-driver interfaces","Drivers for specific hardware devices"]
},{
numb: 371, 
question:"The scheduling strategy where each process in the queue is given a certain amount of time. After this time has elapsed, the process is preempted and added to the end of the ready queue is referred to as: *", 
answer: "Round-Robin",
options: [
"Prioritization","All of the other choices","LIFO","Round-Robin"]
},{
numb: 372, 
question:"In terms of main memory efficiency the method of 'Backing up pages dynamically' in comparison with the method of 'Paging to a static swap area' is *", 
answer: "Worse",
options: [
"Better","Worse","Equal","Nearly equal"]
},{
numb: 373, 
question:"What is the correct approach with the 'No preemption condition' to prevent Deadlock? *", 
answer: "Take resources away",
options: [
"Order resources numerically","Spool everything","Take resources away","Request all resources initially"]
},{
numb: 374, 
question:"Assuming that it takes 10 nsec to copy a byte, how much time does it take to completely rewrite the screen of a 1200 x 800 pixels graphics with 24- bit color? *", 
answer: "28.8 msec",
options: [
"28.8 micro-sec","288 msec","28.8 msec","288 micro-sec"]
},{
numb: 375, 
question:"Strategy used for dumping a disk to tapes is: *", 
answer: "Both physical dump and logical dump",
options: [
"Both physical dump and logical dump","Physical dump","Logical dump","None of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 376, 
question:"Some systems increase the priority of jobs that have been in the system for an unusually long time to expedite their exit, which is known as ____.? *", 
answer: "Aging",
options: [
"Accelerated priority","Bumping","Lagging","Aging"]
},{
numb: 377, 
question:"Five batch jobs A through E, arrive at a computer center at almost the same time. They have estimated running times of 8, 6, 2, 10, and 4 minutes. Their (externally determined) priorities are 3, 5, 2, 1, and 4, respectively, with 5 being the highest priority. Determine the average turnaround time for priority scheduling. Ignore process switching overhead. *", 
answer: "16.8 minutes",
options: [
"6 minutes","16.8 minutes","12.8 minutes","18.8 minutes"]
},{
numb: 378, 
question:"A computer uses a programmable clock in square-wave mode. If 500 MHz crystal is used, what should be the value of the holding register to achieve a clock resolution of 10 msec (Clock tick)? *", 
answer: "5,000,000",
options: [
"50,000,000","5,000,000","500,000","50,000"]
},{
numb: 379, 
question:"Which is not a goal of a scheduling algorithm for batch systems? *", 
answer: "Response time",
options: [
"CPU utilization","Turnaround time","Response time","Throughput"]
},{
numb: 380, 
question:"Which does the power of CPU decrease to if it run at half speed? *", 
answer: "None of the other choices",
options: [
"1/2","1/4","None of the other choices","1/8"]
},{
numb: 381, 
question:"How much cylinder skew is needed for a 7200- RPM (rotate per minute) disk with the track-to-track seek time of 1 msec? The disk has 200 sectors of 512 bytes on each track. *", 
answer: "24 sectors",
options: [
"36 sectors","12 sectors","24 sectors","18 sectors"]
},{
numb: 382, 
question:"Which solutions are used to solve the shared libraries? *", 
answer: "Position-independent code",
options: [
"Static reallocation and position-independent code","None of the other choices","Relocation on the fly and position-independent code","Position-independent code"]
},{
numb: 383, 
question:"Which is not attribute of MS-DOS file? *", 
answer: "Lock",
options: [
"Lock","Read-Only","Hidden, System","Archived"]
},{
numb: 384, 
question:"To specify an address in this segmented memory, the _____ form is used *", 
answer: "<segment-number, offset>",
options: [
"<physical address, offset>","<virtual address, offset>","<segment-number, offset>","<process, offset>"]
},{
numb: 385, 
question:"Which deadlock condition does 'Take resources away' attack? *", 
answer: "No preemption",
options: [
"No preemption","Mutual exclusion","Circular-wait condition","Hold and wait"]
},{
numb: 386, 
question:"An operation concerning Stable Storage is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Stable Reads","Crash recovery","Stable writes","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 387, 
question:"Which ways are used to keep track of free block in disk space management? *", 
answer: "Both linked list method and bitmap method",
options: [
"Both linked list method and bitmap method","A linked list method","None of the other choices","A bitmap method"]
},{
numb: 388, 
question:"Which is space efficiency, if 4KB-file using file system with 8KB-block? *", 
answer: "50%",
options: [
"75%","100%","50%","25%"]
},{
numb: 389, 
question:"Of the three components of access time in a disk, ____ is the longest. *", 
answer: "Seek time",
options: [
"Transfer time","Seek time","Delay time","Search time"]
},{
numb: 390, 
question:"Which RAID level employs a Hamming code to correct single bit errors and detect double bit errors? *", 
answer: "2",
options: [
"3","1","4","2"]
},{
numb: 391, 
question:"In modern printing systems, a disk accepts output from several users, Deadlock occurs when ____. *", 
answer: "c. The printer needs all of a job's output before it will begin printing, but the spooling system fills the available disk space with only partially completed output.",
options: [
"a. The network connection for the printer overflows with too many requests to use the printer.","b. Too many users attempt to access the printer at the same time.","c. The printer needs all of a job's output before it will begin printing, but the spooling system fills the available disk space with only partially completed output.","d. The buffer fills up with too many print jobs and the printer cannot decide which one to print."]
},{
numb: 392, 
question:"Which of the following is an Operating System component? *", 
answer: "Process Management",
options: [
"Process Management","Speed Management","Space Management","Time Management"]
},{
numb: 393, 
question:"The Joliet Extensions provide ________ *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"Directory nesting deeper than 8 levels","All of the other choices","Directory names with extensions","Long file name supported Unicode character"]
},{
numb: 394, 
question:"An algorithm designed to detect starvation by tracking how long each job has been waiting for resources is the same concept as ____. *", 
answer: "Aging",
options: [
"Preemption","Aging","Round robin","Deadlock"]
},{
numb: 395, 
question:"Multiprogramming increases processor efficiency by *", 
answer: "Taking advantage of time wasted by long wait I/O handling",
options: [
"Increasing processor speed","Eliminating all idle processor cycles","Taking advantage of time wasted by long wait I/O handling","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 396, 
question:"Page replacement algorithms determine *", 
answer: "which page to remove to provide space for an incoming page",
options: [
"when the system should update page table entries","how many pages should be added to main memory","which page to remove to provide space for an incoming page","which pages should be brought into memory because a process is likely to reference them soon"]
},{
numb: 397, 
question:"Which of the following process state transitions is illegal? *", 
answer: "blocked -> running",
options: [
"running -> ready","blocked -> ready","ready -> running","blocked -> running"]
},{
numb: 398, 
question:"An example of the key differences that can exist across (and even in) classes of I/O devices is: *", 
answer: "All of the other choices",
options: [
"All of the other choices","Data rate","Data representation","Error conditions"]
},{
numb: 399, 
question:"Which is NOT a file attribute? *", 
answer: "Shape",
options: [
"Time of Access","Owner","Shape","Size"]
},{
numb: 400, 
question:"If in a resource-allocation graph, each resource type has exactly one instance, which of the following indicates a deadlock situation? *", 
answer: "The graph has at least one cycle",
options: [
"The graph has at least one cycle","The graph is not connected","The graph has no cycle","The graph is connected"]
},{
numb: 401, 
question:"The ___ is the essential component of the operating system that remains in RAM when your computer is powered on. *", 
answer: "kernel",
options: [
"system file","registry","core","kernel"]
},{
numb: 402, 
question:"A fetched instruction is normally loaded into *", 
answer: "Instruction Register",
options: [
"None of the other choices","Program Counter","Accumulator","Instruction Register"]
},{
numb: 403, 
question:"A file is generally defined to be: *", 
answer: "A collection of similar records",
options: [
"A collection of similar records","A collection of related fields","A basic element of data","All of the other choices"]
},{
numb: 404, 
question:"Which of the following is not a CPU scheduling criterion? *", 
answer: "Burst time",
options: [
"Throughput","CPU utilization","Burst time","Response time"]
},{
numb: 405, 
question:"The interface between the operating system kernel and the user programs is defined by the set of ___ that the operating system provides *", 
answer: "System calls",
options: [
"System calls","Processes","Functions","Threads"]
},{
numb: 406, 
question:"Which of the following is not a condition for deadlocks? *", 
answer: "Preemption",
options: [
"Hold and Wait","Preemption","Mutual exclusion","Circular Wait"]
},{
numb: 407, 
question:"Which of the following information bits in the entry of page table is false? *", 
answer: "Mode bit",
options: [
"Protection bit","Present/absent bit","Mode bit","Modified bit"]
},{
numb: 408, 
question:"Which of the following information bits in the entry of page table is used to indicate what kinds of access are permitted? *", 
answer: "Protection bit",
options: [
"Modified bit","Protection bit","Present/absent bit","Caching disabled"]
},